准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
水母捕手
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
啊
Ah
又是裤头村水母田美好的一天
another beautiful day
in Bikini Bottom's own Jellyfish Fields
好一个天然淳朴的世界
an untamed world of natural order
水母田
母口数 四百万
小水母们在此
where the little jellyfish jellies
畅游于海景之间
roam free across the salty seascape
但凡有水母的地方
And where there is jellyfish
就会有水母捕手
there is the jellyfish hunter
你是我今天捉到的第十二只
You're my 12th catch of the day
我要叫你小十二
I'm going to call you Twelvy
水母酱
我挠我挠
Kitchy-kitchy-koo
再见  小十二
Bye, Twelvy
是你啊
It's you
我们又见面了
Well, it's just you and me again
田里水母我都至少捉过还取名过一次
I've caught and named every jellyfish
in this field at least once
除了你  无名氏
except you, No-name
放马过来啊
捉到了
Gotcha
真见鬼  怎么做到的
Barnacles, how did he do that?
总有一天我会捉到无名氏
Some day I'll catch ol' No-name
蟹堡王
我要吃午饭了  蟹老板
I'm going on my lunch break, Mr. Krabs
最多只能吃五分钟
You got five minutes
比昨天还多了一分钟
One more minute than yesterday
海绵宝宝准备发射
SpongeBob ready for launch
水母酱
好吃
Yum
好耶
Oh, yeah
兄弟  那是什么东西
Hey, buddy, what the heck is that?
这是个洞  先生
Why, this is a hole, good sir
我身为一个海绵  通常都
You see, I am a sponge, and we typically
不是那东西  是那东西
Not that, that
只是个蟹黄堡而已
It's just a little old Krabby Patty
里面抹了水母酱
smothered in jellyfish jelly
我叫它  水母酱蟹黄堡
I call it a "Krabby Patty with jellyfish jelly"
我可以尝尝吗
Could I try some?
可以
Sure
太神了
Amazing
我一定要广而告之
I've got to tell someone about this
大家听我说
Hey, all you people
能不能听我说
won't you listen to me?
我刚吃了个三明治
I just had a sandwich
不是一般的三明治
no ordinary sandwich
是加了水母酱的三明治
A sandwich filled with jellyfish jelly
老兄  一定要尝尝这个三明治
Hey, man, you got to try this sandwich
不是一般的三明治
It's no ordinary sandwich
是全海洋最好吃的三明治
It's the tastiest sandwich in the sea
感谢
Thank you
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
谁又在放章鱼哥的唱片了
Who's playing Squidward's records again?
没人在放  蟹老板
No one, Mr. Krabs
我只是在跟客人分享我的水母酱
I was just sharing my jellyfish jelly
with the customers
拿去吃吧  蟹老板
Here, Mr. Krabs
带你的味蕾来趟旅行
send your taste buds on a journey
竟敢乱改我蟹黄堡的配方
Messin' with the patty's formula
你那是叛变
That's mutiny
我得要
Why, I ought to
先生  这是我吃过最好吃的东西了
Sir, this is the greatest thing I've ever eaten
以后午餐我都来这边吃
I'm going to come back here for lunch
后半辈子每天都吃
every day for the rest of my life
钱
兄弟  你没事吧
Hey, buddy, you all right?
没事吧  蟹老板
You okay, Mr. K?
海绵宝宝  我给你安排一项任务
SpongeBob, I got a proposition for you
你去给我捉
How's about you go catch me
几只那种钱母过来
some of those little money fish?
天啊  带薪捉水母
Oh, boy, getting paid to jelly-fish
这可是我一生的梦想
that's my life's dream
你梦想不可能实现
Well, keep dreamin'--
只能空闲时间捉  不给工资
this'll be on your time
遵命  老板
Aye, aye, sir
快去给我捉水母
Now, go get me some jellyfish
动作
and make it
快
Quick
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
还得要再多点
we're going to need more
单单一只水母可不够
than one puny jellyfish
可是老板  你要多少只水母
But, sir, how many jellyfish do you need?
海绵宝宝  整个生态系统里
SpongeBob, we have a whole ecosystem
全都是饿肚子的金主顾客
full of hungry payin' customers
不会吧
Oh, no
你该不会是
Don't tell me
再也不为客人着想了
you've stopped carin' for the customers
没这回事
No, never
那就出去
Then go out there
给我多捉水母过来
and get me some more jellies
好  蟹老板
Okay, Mr. Krabs
务必要让水母舒服点
Just make sure the jellyfish are comfortable
水母都比较敏感
they are all so sensitive
我会让水母舒服点的
I'll keep them comfortable all right
舒服住进我钱包
inside me wallet
水母田
水母给你  蟹老板
Here you go, Mr. Krabs
水母酱堡之家
我还要再多点  小子
I'm going to need more than that, boy
多点水母  蟹老板
More jellies, Mr. Krabs
还不够
That'll never do--
多点
more
招租
多点  海绵宝宝
More, SpongeBob
多这个字你是哪不懂了
What don't you understand about "more?"
多点
More
水母田
母口数 零
已经没得捉了
Well, there's no more
这才叫捉水母
Now, that's jellyfishing
感觉好像有谁
It feels like somebody
想给我推销东西
wants to sell me something
就跟你说他发现我们了
I told you he was on to us
你推销的东西我都没兴趣
I'm not interested in anything you're selling
真的有种感觉
It sure felt like
我一定是工作太勤奋了
I must be working too hard
我来接  小蜗
I'll get it, Gary
喂  海绵宝宝家
Hello, SpongeBob's house
我是海绵宝宝
SpongeBob speaking
喂
Hello?
打错了
A wrong number
估计是小蜗忘交电费了
I guess Gary forgot to pay the electric bill
小蜗  是你吗
Gary, is that you?
小蜗
Gary?
对
Yeah
好办法  小蜗
Good idea, Gary
厨房里可能有蜡烛
There's probably some candles in the kitchen
哎哟
Hello
这是什么
what's this?
你是怎么进来的  美食
How did you get in here, oh, delicious one?
吃点小点心就不至于太紧张了
A little snack will calm my nerves
蓝水母酱蟹黄堡
A Krabby Patty with blue jelly
蓝水母
Blue jelly?
你好  无名氏
Hello, No-name
有什么事
what's happening?
无名氏  放我出去
No-name, let me out
你想拿我怎么样
What are you going to do with me?
恶心
P-U
什么怪味这么像大企业
what smells like big business?
我不记得有那家工厂
I don't remember that factory
水母酱
这是什么可怕的地方
What is this horrible place?
我挠我挠
Kitchy-kitchy-koo
是怎样的怪物造就了这么个可怕场景
What kind of monster is responsible for this horror?
没错  小的们
That's it, boys
让特值钱的水母酱一直流下去
keep that gelatinous gold a-flowin'
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
不
No
我总算知道你为什么带我来这了
Now I know why you brought me here
可我们能怎么办
But what can we do?
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
别再疯下去了
Stops this madness
马上停手吧
Stop it right now
事情不是你看到的那样  海绵宝宝
This isn't what it looks like, SpongeBob
那个
Why, uh
我们只是
we're just, uh
在开茶会
having a little tea party
天啊  茶会
Oh, boy, a tea party
你骗我  蟹老板
You tricked me, Mr. Krabs
我本来不会把水母全捉来
I wouldn't have collected all those jellyfish
要不是知道水母会有这种下场
had I known that this was their fate
这样不对
This isn't right
水母需要开阔的空间  还有新鲜的空气
pJellyfish need wide open space and fresh air
你别急  小子
Easy, boy
你拿那个想干什么
what are you doin' with that?
我好久以前就该这么做了
Something that should have been done a long time ago
不
No
门上的螺栓吵得我好难受
The squeaky bolt on this door was driving me crazy
现在  我要解放这些水母
And now, I'm going to set these jellyfish free
你放不来
Well, you can't--
这门是声控的
the door is voice-activated
想让它开  只能等我说开
and it will only open if I say "open"
声控开关
关
开
自由了
Freedom
你们绝对抓不到我
You'll never catch me
什么
What?
就不该盲目跟风健身
Blasted exercise craze
再见了  朋友们
Good-bye, friends
以后不卖水母酱了
I'm taking jelly off the menu
卖水母酱可把他给坑惨了
He really got burned on that deal
本来就该这样
All is as it should be
我保证以后再也不用这张网了
I promise never to use this net
除非是要做运动
for anything but pure sport again
水母从来就不应该让人抓走
Jellyfish aren't meant to be captured forever
无名氏
Oh, No-name
我现在应该可以给你取名了
I guess I can name you now
我要叫你
I'll call you
朋友
Friend
厨师运动会
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
欢迎各位体育迷
Welcome, sports fans
观赏第21届
to the 21st
裤头村年度厨师运动会
Annual Bikini Bottom Fry Cook Games
快餐体育场
我宣布厨师运动会
I declare these Fry Cook Games
开幕
open
请稍候
我宣布厨师运动会
I declare these Fry Cook Games
开幕
open
第21届厨师运动会正式开幕
So begin the 21st Fry Cook Games
我是个写实风鱼头
I'm a realistic fish head
裤头村快餐体育场天气晴好
and it's a beautiful day
here at Bikini Bottom's Fast Food Coliseum
各地运动员纷至沓来
They come from everywhere
微波炉的嗡嗡声
microwaves hum
肉饼的滋滋声
patties sizzle
以及保温灯  让快餐精神又温又潮
and heat lamps keep the fast food spirit warm and soggy
但本次的焦点在于一场激烈竞争
But the real story is the bitter rivalry
竞争双方是两位前任参赛者
between former competitors
蟹堡王的蟹老板
Mr. Krabs of The Krusty Krab
以及海之霸的痞老板
and Plankton, of the Chum Bucket
谁会忘记当年
Who could forget the year
蟹老板在五百腌椰菜级举重一举夺魁
Mr. Krabs won gold for this 500-pickle clean and jerk?
反正痞老板没放心上
Not Plankton
还是当年痞老板打动众多观众的壮举
Or when Plankton won the hearts of millions
完美完成全套洋葱圈体操动作
by performing this perfect onion ring routine
即便断了一根触角也在坚持
with a broken antenna?
反正蟹老板并不感动
Krabs wasn't moved
最新消息称  今年
And now, late word is that this year
将有一位新人代表蟹堡王参赛
the Krusty Krab will be represented
by a new competitor
今天可能将是他青春中最美好的一天
on what is perhaps the greatest day of his young life
今天可能是
This is perhaps
我青春中最美好的一天  蟹老板
the greatest day of my young life, Mr. Krabs
我居然会代表蟹堡王
I can't believe I'm representing the Krusty Krab
参加厨师运动会
in the Fry Cook Games
能够摘金  就能取得荣耀
To bring home the gold is to bring honor and glory
带给蟹堡王
to the Krusty Krab
进而免费宣传  吸引顾客
And all that free publicity will bring in customers
千万不能输
So don't lose
遵命  蟹老板
Aye, aye, Mr. Krabs
蟹堡王
Krusty-Krab
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
蟹堡王
Krusty-Krab
你是要挪动大地吗
Are you trying to move the ground?
你那样挪不动的
You'll never move it like that
必须要从地下
You got to get under
入手
neath it
搞什么  派大星
Come on, Patrick
我是在为运动会做训练
I'm trying to train for the Games
游  戏
游戏
Games?
我能玩吗
Can I play?
抱歉  派大星
Sorry, Patrick
你必须先当上厨师
you have to be a fry cook
当上厨师
Be a fry cook?
就那样吗
Is that all I gotta do?
太简单了
That'll be easy
你说简单是什么意思
What do you mean, "easy"?
这有什么难的
How hard can it be?
不是随便什么人都可以当得上厨师
They don't let just anybody be a fry cook
我们可是精英部队
We're an elite corps
拜托
Come on--
你就只是翻个肉饼而已
you're just flipping patties
翻这个动作可没那么简单
Flipping is not as easy as it sounds
还是回家去吧  派大星
Why don't you go home, Patrick?
你可以去参加
You can compete in
躺石头地下一整天运动会
the Laying-Under-A-Rock-All-Day Games
起码我不会抹指甲
At least I don't polish my fingernails
把话收回去
You take that back
指甲指甲指甲
Fingernails, fingernails, fingernails
你连指甲都没有
You don't even have fingernails
我不敢相信我听到的话
I cannot believe what I am hearing
怎么可能听得见
How can you hear it?
你还没耳朵呢
You don't have ears, either
你
You
大洞  大洞
Holes, holes
尖头
Cone-head
黄块块
Yellow
粉星星
Pink
我要去找厨师工作去了
I'm going to get a job as a fry cook
一定会很简单
and it'll be easy
随便你
Fine
蟹堡王
Krusty-Krab
空气中弥漫着什么味道
What's that smell in the air?
我闻到了痞老板
I smell Plankton
是吗
Oh, yeah?
我味道可
Well, I smell
味确实重
He's right
我就爱捣乱
I love messing things up
准备好要决一死战了吗  老螃蟹
Are you ready to do or die, Krabs?
向来都准备好了  痞老板
Always ready, Plankton
准备好了
always ready
很好  因为今天
Good, because today
海之霸要把你打得
the Chumbucket is going to kick
落花流水
your carapace
自以为是
That's what you think
我手上还有位冠军
But I got me a champion--
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
露一手
Show him
看看他
Look at him
状态绝佳
in his prime
你绝对没机会赢的
You ain't got no chance
你错就错在这里  老螃蟹
That's where you're wrong, Krabs
因为我  也有个冠军
for I, too, have a champion
女士们先生们  全体目光
Ladies and gentlemen, turn your attention
向西南侧通道看齐
to the southwest corridor
另一边
Other way
傻子一群
Imbeciles
然后
And
别转了
stop
完美
Perfect
代表海之霸上场的这位
Representing the Chumbucket
是个超级可怕超级恐怖的生物
a creature so fearsome, so terrible
并且体积大得吓人
so mind-bendingly large
可能会让场下某些体弱的观众
that those of you with weak constitutions
怕得想逃出体育场
may want to leave the stadium
我要逃走
I gotta get out of here
太晚了
Too late
不管有没有准备好  他都要来了
Ready or not, here he comes
害怕吧颤抖吧  愚蠢的凡人
Quake with fear, you mortal fools
请大家鞠躬致敬
Bow down before the awesome might of
这个大个子背上的才是真正的参赛者
this huge guy who's carrying the real contestant
派大星
Patrick Star
派大星  你来这干什么
Patrick, what are you doing here?
你又不是厨师
You're not a fry cook
我当然是了  优秀宝宝先生
Yes, I am Mr. SpongeBob-Superior Pants
你看
Check it out
海之霸
派大星
我已经给海之霸工作了
I been working for the Chumbucket
差不多有五分钟了
for almost five minutes
那也没什么大不了
Well, it doesn't matter anyway
反正你快输到去喝西北风了
'cause you're going to eat my dust
要喝也是喝我自己的西北风
I'm eating my own dust
那也得我先
Not if I eat it first
黄块块
Yellow
粉星星
Pink
我不敢相信  蟹老板
I can't believe it, Mr. Krabs
派大星明明还是我朋友
I thought Patrick was my friend
朋友
Friend?
在这边就不是了
Not in here he ain't
什么意思
What do you mean?
他只是表面朋友
He's not really your friend
真的吗
He's not?
他现在就在计划打垮你
He's plotting your downfall right now
有这回事
He is?
他要在背后捅你刀子
He's going to stab you in the back
不可能
He wouldn't
当然可能了
Of course he would
你看人家
Just look at him
方块
Square
恶魔的形状
the shape of evil
那完全是对你职业技能的大不敬
It's a mockery of your profession
难道要眼睁睁看着个冒牌厨师
Are we going to let some pretender
抢走本该属于蟹堡王的荣耀吗
take away what belongs to the Krusty Krab?
不要
No
那就强势起来
Then get mean
我很强势
I'm mean
愤怒起来
Get angry
我很愤怒
I'm angry
现在上场
Now get out there
赢得
And win
那个
That
奖牌
Medal
第一项赛事
Our first event
油炸王
油锅撑杆跳
the deep-fry pole vault
为蟹堡王赢得比赛
Win this one for the Krusty Krab
为了蟹堡王
For the Krusty Krab
我叫你赢  你就必须赢
Win this one because I told you to
你叫我必须赢
Because you told me to
炸鱼条
Fish sticks
来买炸鱼条
Get your fish sticks here
炸鱼条
第二项赛事
The next event
巧克力跳水
the chocolate high-dive
给正牌厨师让个道  派大星
Make way for the real fry cook, Patrick
这次跳水  海绵宝宝将要尝试
For his dive, SpongeBob will be attempting
双棍香蕉软巧克力糖冰棍跳
a full banana fudge-pop with two sticks
现在  一片寂静
And now, absolute silence
激灵
I scream
为了冰淇淋
for ice cream
完美入水
Perfect entry
还裹上了烤杏仁
And toasted almonds--
意想不到
that's unexpected
他站稳了
He stuck it
看他裹得多均匀
And just look at that even coating
超越我吧
Top that
粉星星
Pinky
杏仁
Almonds?
真该死  太有才华了
Curse him, that's good
然而太高雅  场下大众未必欣赏得来
but perhaps a bit too highbrow for this crowd
他自以为高人一等
He thinks he's better than them
高你一等
Better than you
快上台给人家瞧瞧
Now get up there and show him
咱普通百姓会怎么做牛奶冰淇淋
how the common man prepares his frozen dairy treats
派大星将要重拾旧爱
Patrick will be resurrecting an old favorite
单筒草莓甜筒  蘸上巧克力
the single-scoop strawberry cone with a chocolate dip
看他此般聚精会神
Just look at that concentration
入水不是很行
A little shaky on that entry--
但是看看那形体
but just look at that form
接招吧  黄块块
Take that, Yellow Boy
你迟早笑不出来  粉星星
Laugh while you can, Pinky
比赛还没结束呢
It's not over yet
你自以为会那样
That's what you think
但是比赛还没结束呢
but it's not over yet
千磅番茄酱
比赛还没结束
It's not over yet
双方比分持平  进入最后一项赛事
With the score tied, we go to our final event
面包摔跤
Bun Wrestling
谁将会摘金呢
Who will take home the gold?
是蟹堡王的蟹老板
Mr. Krabs of the Krusty Krab?
别忘了  他叫你黄块块
Don't forget, he called ye yellow
还是海之霸的痞老板
Or Plankton, of the Chumbucket?
别忘了  他叫你粉星星
Don't forget, he called you pink
我不管海之霸了
Forget the Chumbucket--
这个是私人恩怨
this is personal
海之霸
派大星
大星
不
No
我的名字不叫  大星
My name's not "Rick"
我不喜欢你
I don't like you
我更不喜欢你
I don't like you more
我从来不喜欢你
I never liked you
我一千倍不喜欢你
I a thousand times never liked you
粉星星
Pink
黄块块
Yellow
黄的
粉的
Pink?
你还在乎我
You do care
一起保证再也不要打架了  兄弟
Let's promise never to fight again, buddy
好啊  好朋友
Yeah, pal
一起回家吧
let's go home
你们要去哪
Where you going?
快回来拼个你死我活
Get back here and kill each other
你是我最好的朋友
You're my best friend ever
你也是  派大星
You, too, Patrick
我内裤刚买的时候还是白的
You know, these were white when I bought them